Enchanted Christmas is a romance, tv movie film directed by Terry Cunningham.
Weeks before Christmas, interior designer Laura is sent to her hometown
of Santa Fe, New Mexico to remodel a landmark hotel.
As Laura is kept busy with the renovations, her 8-year-old daughter Nicole is
introduced to the art of salsa dancing at a local dance studio.
Laura is surprised to find that the studio’s owner is Ricardo, her old
high school sweetheart and former salsa dance partner.
When Laura and Ricardo reconnect, sparks fly on and off the dance floor.
The beautiful Christmas traditions of New Mexico become the
backdrop for spirited dancing and unexpected romance.
Laura Trudeau, played by Alexa PenaVega.
Ricardo Archuleta, played by Carlos PenaVega.
Scott Schaeffer, played by Randy Wayne.
Taylor, played by Chelsie Hightower.
Manuel Montoya, played by Rene Rivera.
Nikki Trudeau, played by Jaynee-Lynne Kinchen.
Enchanted is a 2007 American live-action animated musical fantasy romantic
comedy film directed by Kevin Lima and written by Bill Kelly.
Co-produced by Walt Disney Pictures, Josephson Entertainment, and Right Coast Productions, the film stars Amy Adams, Patrick
Dempsey, James Marsden, Timothy Spall, Idina Menzel, and Susan Sarandon, with Julie Andrews as the narrator.
It focuses on an archetypal Disney Princess-to-be named Giselle, who is exiled from her animated world into the
live-action world of the New York City metropolitan area, where she falls in love with a divorce lawyer.
The film is both an homage to and a self-parody of Disney's animated features, making numerous references to past works
through the combination of live-action filmmaking, traditional animation, and computer-generated imagery.
It also marks the return of traditional animation to a Disney feature film after the
company's decision to move entirely to computer animation in 2004.
Composer Alan Menken and lyricist Stephen Schwartz, who had written songs for previous Disney films,
wrote and produced the songs of Enchanted, and Menken also composed the film's score.
The animated sequences were produced at James Baxter Animation in Pasadena, while
filming of the live-action segments took place around New York City.
Enchanted premiered at the London Film Festival on October 20, 2007, and went
into its wide release in the United States on November 21.
It was critically well-received, established Adams as a leading lady, and
earned more than $340 million worldwide at the box office.
It won three Saturn Awards, Best Fantasy Film, Best
Actress for Adams and Best Music for Menken.
Enchanted also received two nominations at the 65th Golden Globe Awards and
three Best Original Song nominations at the 80th Academy Awards.
This is the first Walt Disney Pictures film to be distributed under the Walt Disney Studios Motion
Pictures banner after Disney retired the Buena Vista brand from its distribution division.
A sequel, Disenchanted, was released on Disney+ on November 18, 2022.
The tone is emotional.